SAM KAUFFMAN "Ok Google, talk to Sam's portfolio"

hello@samvk.com https://samvk.com 860-878-8669 West Hartford, CT 06107

SUMMARY

I'm a web developer who enjoys problem solving, building apps, and bringing designs to life. My go-to technologies right now include **HTML5**, **CSS3**, and **JavaScript**(ESNext) — amped with the help of **React** & **Redux** and **PostCSS** & **Sass** — built with the help of **Webpack** and **Babel**. I also have experience with **Node.js**, **PHP**, and **SQL**.

Feel free to check me out on GitHub at https://github.com/samvk or take a look at my portfolio at https://samvk.com.

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer | Web Application Developer

2016 - Present

Konica Minolta Business Solutions, Windsor, CT

- Responsible for leading a small team in the development and adoption of React & Redux and PostCSS for the new global app store
- Worked closely with QA in an Agile environment to improve the stability, user-interface, and internationalization & localization of the store
- Involved in the full development process from requirements gathering to design, implementation, testing, and maintenance
- Redesigned the app store for an updated look and better user-friendliness making reusable UI components used cross-department to help impose consistency and speed development time

Freelance Web Developer

2015 - 2016

Greater Hartford, CT

- Designing and developing responsive web apps for different types of end-users
- Working closely with clients to translate business needs into clearly-defined goals and requirements
- Enhancing the user experience of existing web apps along with front-end and back-end maintenance

Information Technology Specialist

March 2016 - November 2016

CREC Central, Greater Hartford, CT

- Troubleshooting and resolving issues related to computer software and hardware
- Installing software updates and hardware upgrades on end-user machines

Mathematics Associate Instructor

2015 - 2016

CREC MLC High School, Bloomfield, CT

- Supporting students in the strengthening of math skills and conceptual understandings
- Integrating technology into the classroom to help visualize, analyze, and interpret data
- Gathering school data to track long-term student growth

PROJECTS

Konica Minolta MarketPlace

https://konicaminoltamarketplace.com

Global app store rebuilt from scratch using React & Redux and PostCSS – with a back-end in PHP and Node.js serverless microservices on AWS

Hourglass in seconds

https://chromewebstore.samvk.com/hourglass

A Chrome add-on for Konica Minolta's corporate time-keeping app that simplifies and enhances feature set and increases user-friendliness

Etymology Dictionary

"Ok Google, talk to Etymology Dictionary"

Skill for Google Assistant built with Dialogflow and Node.js – deployed on Firebase – consuming the Oxford Dictionaries API

Portfolio | SamVK

https://samvk.com

My portfolio – rewritten in React – with Node.js + TypeScript for the email service using SES on AWS

EDUCATION

Franklin and Marshall College

Bachelor's in Technical Theatre and Design | graduated cum laude